TEJAS GOKHALE

RESEARCH INTERESTS

I work on computer vision, machine learning, and natural language processing – very often at the wonderful intersection of the three disciplines. My domain expertise lies in *semantic vision*, i.e. building computer vision algorithms that assign "meaning" to what cameras see, with special focus on analyzing and improving the robustness and generalizability of such algorithms.

EDUCATION

Ph.D.Computer Engineering,Advisors: Yezhou Yang, Chitta Baral2018–2023M.S.Electrical and Computer Engineering,Advisor: Aswin Sankaranarayanan2016-2017B.E. (Honors)Electronics and Instrumentation Engineering,2011-2015

PUBLICATIONS

Conference Proceedings

Semantically Distributed Robust Optimization for Vision-and-Language Inference

T. Gokhale, A. Chaudhary, P. Banerjee, C. Baral, Y. Yang

https://arxiv.org/abs/2110.07165

ACL Findings 2022

Generalized but not Robust? Comparing the Effects of Data Modification Methods on Out-of-Domain Generalization and Adversarial Robustness

T. Gokhale, S. Mishra, M. Luo, B. Sachdeva, C. Baral

https://arxiv.org/abs/2203.07653

ACL Findings 2022

Unsupervised Natural Language Inference Using PHL Triplet Generation

N. Varshney, P. Banerjee, T. Gokhale, C. Baral

https://arxiv.org/abs/2110.08438

ACL Findings 2022

To Find Waldo You Need Contextual Cues: Debiasing Who's Waldo

Y. Luo, P. Banerjee, T. Gokhale, Y. Yang, C. Baral

https://arxiv.org/abs/2203.16682

ACL Findings 2022

Improving Biomedical Information Retrieval with Neural Retrievers

M. Luo, A. Mitra, T. Gokhale, C. Baral

https://arxiv.org/abs/2201.07745

AAAI 2022

Weakly Supervised Relative Spatial Reasoning for Visual Question Answering

P. Banerjee, T. Gokhale, Y. Yang, C. Baral

https://arxiv.org/abs/2109.01934

ICCV 2021

WeaQA: Weak Supervision via Captions for Visual Question Answering

P. Banerjee, T. Gokhale, Y. Yang, C. Baral

https://arxiv.org/abs/2012.02356

ACL Findings 2021

Self-Supervised Test-Time Learning for Reading Comprehension

P. Banerjee, T. Gokhale, C. Baral

https://arxiv.org/abs/2103.11263

NAACL 2021

Attribute-Guided Adversarial Training for Robustness to Natural Perturbations

T. Gokhale, R. Anirudh, B. Kailkhura, J. Thiagarajan, C. Baral, Y. Yang

https://arxiv.org/abs/2012.01806

AAAI 2021

Mutant: A Training Paradigm for Out-of-Distribution Generalization in Visual Question Answering

T. Gokhale, P. Banerjee, C. Baral, Y. Yang

https://arxiv.org/abs/2009.08566 EMNLP 2021

Video2commonsense: Generating commonsense descriptions to enrich video captioning

Z. Fang, T. Gokhale, P. Banerjee, C. Baral, Y. Yang

https://arxiv.org/abs/2003.05162 EMNLP 2021

VQA-LOL: Visual question answering under the lens of logic

T. Gokhale, P. Banerjee, C. Baral, Y. Yang

https://arxiv.org/abs/2002.08325 ECCV 2020

Workshop Papers / Pre-Prints

Halluci-Net: Scene Completion by Exploiting Object Co-occurrence Relationships

K. Kulkarni, T. Gokhale, R. Singh, P. Turaga, A. Sankaranarayanan

https://arxiv.org/abs/2004.08614 Al for Content Creation @ CVPR 2021

Cooking With Blocks: A Recipe for Visual Reasoning on Image-Pairs

T. Gokhale, S. Sampat, Z. Fang, Y. Yang, C. Baral

Long version: https://arxiv.org/abs/1905.12042 Vision Meets Cognition @ CVPR 2019

Proposal Writing

An Active Approach for Data Engineering to Improve Vision-Language Tasks

PI: Yezhou Yang, Co-PI: Chitta Baral

(Conceptualized and wrote 2 of 3 research plans)

Accepted and Funded by NSF

Decentralized Authorship Attribution

PI: Chitta Baral Submitted to IARPA

(Conceptualized and wrote 1 of 3 research plans)

EXPERIENCE

Microsoft ResearchMay 2021 - Aug 2021Research Intern(Mentor: Hamid Palangi)

Lawrence Livermore National Labs, Livermore CA May 2021 - Aug 2021

Research Scholar (Mentor: Rushil Anirudh)

Lawrence Livermore National Labs, Livermore CA May 2020 - Aug 2020

Research Scholar (Mentor: Rushil Anirudh)

Snap Inc., Seattle May 2018 - Aug 2018

Research Intern (Mentors: Guru Krishnan & Shree Nayar)

Carnegie Mellon University

Jan 2017 - May 2018

Graduate Student Researcher (Advisor: Aswin Sankaranarayanan)

TEACHING/MENTORING

Teaching Associate, ASU,

CSE310 (Data Struct. & Algorithms), CSE408 (Multimedia Info Systems), CSE110 (Intro to Programming) Masters Thesis Mentor (at ASU),

Abhishek Chaudhary, (AY 2020-21), Huiliang Shao, (AY 2021-22), Maitreya Patel, (AY 2022-23)

Capstone Mentor, mentored 5 BS students in projects on vision & language

Project Mentor, CSE576 - Natural Language Processing, ASU

Project Mentor, CSE598 - Perception in Robotics, ASU

Instructor, CTE: Advanced Image Processing, BITS Pilani Goa Campus

AY 2019-20

Spring 2022

Spring 2015

INVITED TALKS

Mar'22, (Guest Lecture) "Introduction to Generalization in Semantic Vision"

Sep'21, (Invited) "Robust Visual Understanding",

AUGUML Club
Aug'19, "Vision Beyond Pixels", IJCAI Doctoral Consortium,

Jul'19, "Reasoning about Objects and Actions via Block-Play",

Apr'18, (Invited) "Deep Learning Methods in Imaging and Computer Vision",

BITS Goa

SERVICE / LEADERSHIP

Reviewer: NeurIPS (2022), ICLR (2022), ECCV (2022), AAAI (2021-22), *ACL/Rolling Review (2021-22), WACV (2022), IROS (2022), ICRA (2019-22), IEEE RA-L (2020), Springer MVAP (2020) Organizer, O-DRUM: Workshop on Open-Domain Retrieval under Multi-Modal Settings, Website CVPR 2022 Organizer, 2021 Frontiers of V&L Seminar Series, Website, ASU Founder, Summer Vision Reading Group, Website, multi-university initiative Volunteer, 2019 Southwest Robotics Symposium, Tempe AZ Volunteer, International Conference on Machine Learning 2020, Virtual Advisor, ASU Machine Learning Club, **ASU Mentor**, Graduate Student Mentorship Program, ASU Student Mentor, Peer Mentorship Program BITS Pilani

AWARDS

CVPR 2022 Doctoral Consortium CVPR 2022 ICLR Highlighted Reviewer ICLR 2022 SCAI Doctoral Fellowship (ASU), Spring 2022, Spring 2021, 2020 Engineering Graduate Fellowship, (ASU Engineering), Spring 2020 Graduate College Travel Award, (ASU), for ECCV 2022 ICCV 2021, EMNLP 2020, ECCV 2020 IJCAI 2019 Doctoral Consortium, **IJCAI 2019** Inducted, IEEE Eta Kappa Nu, Sigma Chapter (CMU), Jan 2017 National Talent Scholarship (Govt. of India), 2007-2015

REFERENCES

Yezhou YangAssistant ProfessorArizona State University,yz.yang@asu.eduChitta BaralProfessorArizona State University,chitta@asu.eduRushil AnirudhResearch ScientistLawrence Livermore National Laboratoryanirudh1@llnl.gov